<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Develop on philseguin.com</title><link>https://iuffxguy.github.io/categories/develop/</link><description>Recent content in Develop on philseguin.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 10:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iuffxguy.github.io/categories/develop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building and Launching My First iPhone App with AI</title><link>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/freeze-dry-tracker-app/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/freeze-dry-tracker-app/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For years I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to not only create an iPhone app but go through the entire process of getting it into the app store. Years ago I got very close with a custom Tesla app I built, but given it was built on unsupported APIs I always felt uneasy launching it and then dealing with the headache of APIs constantly breaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the advancements in AI tools lately, I figured this was as good a time as any to finally make it happen. Using Cursor as my AI coding companion, I was able to build an entire app from scratch and finally get something launched!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building a Collection of iPad-Friendly Games for Kids</title><link>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/building-ipad-games-for-kids/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/building-ipad-games-for-kids/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about creating a collection of simple, engaging games that my kids can play on their iPad. Not the typical app store downloads with ads and in-app purchases, but clean, educational web-based games that just work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🎮 &lt;a href="https://iuffxguy.github.io/kidsgames/"&gt;Visit the Kids Games Hub&lt;/a&gt; to play!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-vision"&gt;The Vision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to build a series of HTML5 games that are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Touch-optimized&lt;/strong&gt;: Designed specifically for tablet interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educational&lt;/strong&gt;: Subtly teaching concepts like counting, colors, patterns, and problem-solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distraction-free&lt;/strong&gt;: No ads, no external links, no data collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offline-capable&lt;/strong&gt;: Can be saved as bookmarks and work without internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progressive&lt;/strong&gt;: Games that adapt difficulty as kids improve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-web-games"&gt;Why Web Games?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of native iOS apps, I&amp;rsquo;m going with web games for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Found the first mobile game I ever built</title><link>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/ti-83-programmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 21:40:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/ti-83-programmer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href="https://www.ticalc.org/archives/files/fileinfo/2/280.html"&gt;https://www.ticalc.org/archives/files/fileinfo/2/280.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1997, a &amp;lsquo;mobile&amp;rsquo; device was a bit different than today&amp;rsquo;s amazing phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By learning TI-83 Basic I got my first introduction into loops, conditional statements, &amp;ldquo;functions&amp;rdquo;, and much more. It was all so fascinating to me that I could build programs and play them all on this same device that I could bring anywhere with me (including school).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was weird about coming across this was my close friends know I have always had a strange obsession with horse racing. I had forgotten that I built this betting/racing simulator on my TI-83 when I was 15.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>