<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on philseguin.com</title><link>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on philseguin.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Collection of iPad-Friendly Games for Kids</title><link>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/building-ipad-games-for-kids/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/building-ipad-games-for-kids/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about creating a collection of simple, engaging games that my kids can play on their iPad. Not the typical app store downloads with ads and in-app purchases, but clean, educational web-based games that just work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>🎮 &lt;a href="https://iuffxguy.github.io/kidsgames/">Visit the Kids Games Hub&lt;/a> to play!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-vision">The Vision&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The goal is to build a series of HTML5 games that are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Touch-optimized&lt;/strong>: Designed specifically for tablet interaction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Educational&lt;/strong>: Subtly teaching concepts like counting, colors, patterns, and problem-solving&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Distraction-free&lt;/strong>: No ads, no external links, no data collection&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Offline-capable&lt;/strong>: Can be saved as bookmarks and work without internet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Progressive&lt;/strong>: Games that adapt difficulty as kids improve&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="why-web-games">Why Web Games?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Instead of native iOS apps, I&amp;rsquo;m going with web games for several reasons:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Parkinsons Law</title><link>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/parkinsons-law/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 06:51:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/parkinsons-law/</guid><description>&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parkinson%27s_law">https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parkinson%27s_law&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I find this law really interesting because of the many ways it impacts our lives. The idea that things will always find a way to fill the free space you give it makes sense when you think of ways we see this in our everyday lives such as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The extra storage which seemed huge when you first bought your house is now full years later&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Always needing more hard drive space&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A simple task can takes weeks to get done if you give it weeks to get done&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s more interesting to me though is how this applies to companies as well. I have seen this at multiple jobs and its impact can be devastating to your department if you are not aware it is happening. What typically happens is something like this:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Found the first mobile game I ever built</title><link>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/ti-83-programmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 21:40:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://iuffxguy.github.io/posts/ti-83-programmer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="https://www.ticalc.org/archives/files/fileinfo/2/280.html">https://www.ticalc.org/archives/files/fileinfo/2/280.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 1997, a &amp;lsquo;mobile&amp;rsquo; device was a bit different than today&amp;rsquo;s amazing phones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By learning TI-83 Basic I got my first introduction into loops, conditional statements, &amp;ldquo;functions&amp;rdquo;, and much more. It was all so fascinating to me that I could build programs and play them all on this same device that I could bring anywhere with me (including school).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What was weird about coming across this was my close friends know I have always had a strange obsession with horse racing. I had forgotten that I built this betting/racing simulator on my TI-83 when I was 15.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>